#### Contact

muhddanish.28@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/muhddanish (LinkedIn)

# Top Skills

Talent Acquisition
Employee Relations
Technical Recruiting

## Languages

English (Professional Working)

#### Certifications

Hospitality Management

# **Muhammad Danish**

(Looking for new opportunity)

Kuala Lumpur

# Summary

Versatile, Flexibility and motivational goal-oriented personality!

I enjoy working in a fast-paced environment, which requires me to challenge myself by working under pressure and presenting professionally.

Highly developed skills in Recruiting or Placement, Employee Relations, and Hospitality Management. Experience more than 10's years in Recruitment Agencies and Internal Recruiting. Allowing myself to provide good career management services for various clients (Stakeholders/Hiring Managers) and not to forget candidates with assisting their obtained employment

Well exposed to various industries such as Banking & Financial Services, Retails, Call Centre / Customer Service, Consulting, E-Commerce, and Start-up companies.

Expertise in all aspects of full life-cycle recruiting includes sourcing, screening, interviewing, selection, offer negotiation, salary proposal, and others related to the hiring process for positions (entry/ associate/manager/senior manager) roles.

Proactive sourcing throughout Linkedin Recruiter, Networking, Referrals, Applicant tracking system (ATS), and Boolean searches.

#recruiter
#jobopportunity
#lookingnewopportunity

# Experience

PERTUBUHAN KESELAMATAN SOSIAL (PERKESO)

# Temporary Administrator

June 2020 - December 2020 (7 months)

Putrajaya, Putrajaya Federal Territory, Malaysia

- Working closely with the Marketing team and sharing ideas for marketing plans within key objectives of MYFutureJobs (PERKESO)
- Involving and generating content creative for MYFutureJobs at each stage of the campaigns, and reporting results once completed
- To assist senior team members in replying to social media inquiries and complaints about Facebook Messenger.
- Liaising with Vendor (Media) or stakeholders as required and managing the production of marketing materials such as posters (billboard) including ebunting and others
- To Coordinate and assist senior staff for any interview carnival via Online Interview
- Perform various tasks, such as answering telephone calls, receiving, and directing visitors, ordering office supplies, maintaining the office facilities running smoothly, and ensuring that equipment and appliances work properly.

#### Nielsen

Recruitment Consultant

March 2020 - May 2020 (3 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Reason for leaving: Company Downsizing due to COVID -19

- To manage all aspects of full life-cycle recruiting for positions for Malaysia hiring and others ASEAN markets.
- Managing and executing full life-cycle recruitment, including sourcing, screening, interviewing, selection, offer negotiation, salary proposal, and others related to the hiring process
- Identifying passive candidates using creative and innovative recruiting techniques
- Partnering with hiring managers and HR Business Partners to identify and understand key requirements, then build a comprehensive recruiting strategy
- Proactive high-level sourcing, such as LinkedIn Recruiter, networking events, and Boolean searches, and finding passive candidates through multifaceted internet searches and networking
- Managing the recruitment process and applicant flow in our Application Tracking System
- Partnering with hiring managers and business leaders on diversity initiatives and attracting a diverse candidate selection

OYO Malaysia
Senior Talent Acquisition Specialist

March 2019 - March 2020 (1 year 1 month)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Reason for leaving: Company Downsizing (MSS)

- To expertise with recruitment cycle for non-executive, executive, senior and manager roles
- Work closely with HR Manager and Department Manager, to manage hiring recruitment activities for Headquarters and Regions
- To verify all hiring processes (Requisition, Candidate Application, Interviewing, Selection and On-Boarding Candidate)
- Build and manage a market research service for prospective new potential candidate database
- Network to identify new business opportunities through utilizing our strong network and marketing experience
- Work closely with the recruiter's team members to develop and implement relevant attraction plans for specific regions and industries

BGC Malaysia Sdn Bhd Recruitment Specialist February 2018 - March 2019 (1 year 2 months)

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Develop recruiting specifications and business development with the various clients and facilitate recruiting strategy.
- Manage the full-recruitment cycle for hires across all levels, including complex and senior levels. Especially for Banking & Financial Services.
- Work closely with all recruiters to understand the team dynamics and culture recruiting within that context.
- Actively pursue all channels (Internet, networking, social media, etc.) to form a knowledge base of finding the best talent pool of candidates for each role.
- Maximize direct hiring.
- Develop and manage a network of recruitment and referral sources includes professional associations, and vendors to assist in identifying job candidates.

Ria Financial Senior Recruitment Consultant September 2017 - February 2018 (6 months) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

• Effectively demonstrate "Best Practices" and promote brand awareness

- To expertise with recruitment cycle for non-executive, executive, senior, manager, and director roles.
- Work closely with HR Manager and Department Manager, to manage hiring recruitment activities for Headquarters and more than 100 branches (nationwide)
- To verify all hiring processes using TALEO system (Requisition, Candidate Application, Interviewing, Selection and On-Boarding Candidate)
- Build and manage a market research service for prospective new potential candidate database
- Network to identify new business opportunities through utilizing our strong network and marketing experience
- Work closely with the recruiter's team members to develop and implement relevant attraction plans for specific regions and Industries

CareerXcell Sdn Bhd
Talent Acquisition Specialist
November 2013 - September 2017 (3 years 11 months)
Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

- Develop recruiting specifications with the hiring manager and facilitate recruiting strategy.
- Manage the full-recruitment cycle for hires across all levels includes complex and senior levels.
- Work closely with all recruiters to understand team dynamics and culture.
- Actively pursue all channels (Internet, networking, social media, etc.) to form a knowledge base to find the best talent pool of candidates for each particular role.
- Maximize direct hiring.
- Liaise with internal departments and external vendors to close candidates.
- Develop and manage a network of recruitment and referral sources includes universities, professional associations, and vendors to assist in identifying job candidates.
- Provide coaching and guidance to junior-level recruiting staff.
- Manage data integrity and timely entry.
- Process hiring and dealing with client expectations.
- Act as the respected partner to Business unit leaders and HRBPs to support business unit strategy.
- Prioritize amongst multiple requests, conflicting priorities, and short timelines depends upon alignment with line manager and company's strategic direction.
- Maintain and develop key relationships with vendors to provide valuable additional sourcing channels for the company.

### Kelly Services

### **Staffing Consultant**

April 2010 - November 2013 (3 years 8 months)

- Sourcing and screening candidates and maintaining recruitment reports.
- Facilitate interview schedules for the Team Leader and client expectations.
- Work closely with the team members and follow the guideline. And to ensure clients and candidates are well brief with all terms and conditions applied.
- Process hiring and dealing with client expectations.
- Directly liaising with the client such as BPO Solution Company.
- Attending bulk-order as requested from the client.
- Identify the right candidates to be placed and follow the instructions flow recruitment.
- Ensure all orders need to meet up on daily, weekly, and monthly targets.
- · Work with the high pressure and high expectations needed.

Traders Hotel Kuala Lumpur By Shangri-La Corp.

**Customer Service Associate** 

February 2007 - April 2010 (3 years 3 months)

- Responsible for delivering customer orders and requests.
- Manage with team members to ensure all the operations all running smoothly.
- Guide new staff to follow the KPI needed.
- Understand customer requests and resolving customer complaints.

# Education

Universiti Utara Malaysia

Public Management, Public Relations/Image Management · (2020 - 2024)